《犯罪心理》  前情回顧
Previously on "Criminal minds"...
我有位好朋友  德州布里斯科縣的
A good friend of mine, Sheriff Peter Coleman,
彼得·科爾曼警長
down in Briscoe County, Texas,
因一起疑似案件聯系了我
reached out to me about a possible case.
這一個嫖客和兩名妓女都被同一嫌犯所殺
The same unsub killed one john and two prostitutes.
如果你沒法保證我的姑娘們的安全
If you can't make sure my bitches are safe,
那要你何用
then what good are you?
他在賈斯汀·米爾斯之前還有一個身份
Because before he was Justin Mills,
戈登·伯雷爾
he was Gordon Borell,
他曾因割傷手下的妓女而被逮捕過
And he was arrested for cutting one of the ladies he employed.
可是你說不明嫌犯希望我們抓到他并且懲罰他
But you said the unsub wanted us to catch him and punish him.
他真正想要的是讓我們抓住牧師
What he really wanted was for us to catch the preacher.
我們必須告訴他  我們知道他不是兇手
We need to tell him we know he didn't do this.
牧師啊  你看看你都干了些什么
Oh, preacher, what have you gotten yourself into?
有人開火  有人開火
Shots fired! Shots fired!
布萊克
Blake!
里德
Reid!
需要醫護人員
We need a medic now!
失血太多
There's too much blood!
你做的很好
Hey, you're doing great, all right?
你得堅持住  好嗎
Yeah. You gotta stay right here, ok?
看著我  看著我
Eyes on me. Eyes on me.
對
Yeah.
不  不  不
No, no. No.
伊森  伊森
Ethan? Ethan!
睜開眼
Open your eyes.
來人啊
Hurry!
快
嫌犯中槍  重復一遍  嫌犯中槍
Suspect is down. Repeat, suspect is down.
這里我們處理
We got this covered.
你們的一名組員情況不妙
One of yours is in bad shape.
我們走
Let's go.
收到  我們有兩人受傷  他們三人
Copy that. Two of ours, 3 of theirs.
有犧牲人員嗎
Any casualties?
有一個  是科爾曼
One. Coleman.
科爾曼
Coleman?
里德怎么樣了
And what about Reid?
不太妙  正要送他去醫院
Not good. They're taking him to the hospital.
我之后再給你回電話
I'll call you back.
好了  戴瑞  你也得去檢查下傷口
All right, Derek, you should go get that looked at.
我們醫院見
We'll meet you there.
最快到醫院的辦法是走17號高速
Fastest route to the hospital is highway 17.
謝謝
Thanks.
聽起來像燒水壺的聲音
The sound is like a teakettle.
你聽到了嗎
Do you hear it?
什么
What?
里德
Reid.
血壓下降
Pressure's dropping.
脈細速  開放大口徑靜脈通路
Pulse is thready. Starting large-bore I.V.
里德
Reid!
探員  你坐好別動
Agent, you've got to sit back.
你得救救他
You gotta help him, man.
小子  拜托
Kid, come on, now.
堅持住  我就在這
Stay with me. I'm right here.
里德
Reid.
Reid!
堅持住
Stay with me.
犯罪心理
第九季  第二十四集[本季終]
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯  janiceyj  宏奇奇
翻
譯
王二川  小雷_Amber
翻譯  抹茶咖啡  小蠻腰
鳴謝  五哥  孤帆
時間軸  憑陵新月  葵小樹
校對    紫玉
特效&后期  灰灰是菇涼
總監  尼克白
惡魔
Demons
急診室
"當真理被埋葬  它會生長
"When truth is buried, it grows.
會抑制  會積攢相當有爆發力的能量
It chokes. It gathers such an explosive force
有朝一日  破土而出
that on the day it bursts out,
帶著一切重現于世”
it blows up everything with it."
愛彌爾·左拉
Emile Zola.
19世紀后半期法國重要的批判現實主義作家
有消息了嗎
Anything yet?
沒有
No.
如果斯賓塞坐這  時間都夠他讀完兩本書了
Spence would have read like two books by now.
說不定是三本
Maybe 3.
中槍的人本該是我
It should have been me.
也許是我  或者其他人
Or me or any of us.
不
No.
他推開了我
He pushed me out of the way.
-要是他沒挺住  -他會挺過來的
- If he doesn't make it. - He'll make it.
他必須挺過來
He has to.
他還這么年輕
He's just--he's too young.
對  他還有許多要做的事呢
Yeah, there's still things for him to do.
他想要孩子
You know, he wants kids.
你能想象斯賓塞為人父的樣子嗎
Can you imagine Spence as a dad?
那一定是全世界最幸運的小孩了
That'd be the luckiest kid in the world.
肯定
No doubt.
你來了
You made it.
是啊  原來不止我們有關系
Yeah, it turns out we're not the only one that's connected
他認識有飛機的人
and he knows somebody with a plane.
他怎么樣了
How is he?
還在手術中
Still in surgery.
你們現在可以去見摩根探員了
You all can see Agent Morgan now.
如果你們不介意的話  我希望待在這
Well, if you don't mind, I'd really like to stay here.
你一有消息  就通知我
The second you hear anything, call me.
我很快就回來
I'll be right back.
里德怎么樣了
How's Reid?
還在手術中
He's still in surgery.
別動  你在干什么
No! What are you doing?
我才不要傻躺在這
You can bet your ass I'm not gonna just sit around here.
各位  拜托  把我弄出去
Guys, come on, get me out of here.
事實上  你得躺好  稍微等等
Actually, you are. Just hang on a second.
我們先搞清楚現在是什么情況  跟我說說
Just until we figure out what's what. Catch me up.
槍擊開始前  屋內的三名被害人就已死亡
The 3 victims inside were dead before the shooting started.
尸斑已經形成  而且沒有血跡飛濺痕跡
Lividity had set in and there was no blood spatter.
他們不是在那里被殺的
They weren't killed there.
牧師的車上很干凈
The preacher's car was clean,
他不可能用那輛車來轉移尸體
so there's no way he transported bodies in it.
所以你們是對的
So you were right.
他是被陷害的  但是被誰呢
He was being framed. But by whom?
答案就在被害人身上
The answer's in the victims.
貝琳達·克拉克和杰西·摩爾
Belinda Clark and Jesse Moore
和其他人一樣涉嫌賣淫
were both tied to prostitution like the others.
特拉維斯·亨森則是桌球房的常客
Travis Henson was a regular at the pool hall,
但他不在那里工作
but he didn't work there.
我不明白為什么牧師
See, I don't get why the preacher
不出來跟你坦白呢
didn't just come clean with you.
他是個自戀的反社會者
He was a narcissistic sociopath who was cornered,
走投無路了依然覺得自己能夠逃脫
but he still thought that he could get away with it.
一旦他開了第一槍  就下了決心
Once he started shooting, he made his decision.
坦白是不可能了
Coming clean was no longer an option.
我不認為第一槍是他開的
Guys, I don't think he was the first one to shoot.
陷害他的人也在場
Whoever set him up was there.
大膽的推斷  你為什么這么想
That's ballsy. What makes you think that?
因為我很確定
Because I'm pretty sure
里德和我都聽到了第一聲槍響
that Reid and I heard the first shots fired.
我們都在餐廳外面
We were all outside of that diner.
有照片嗎
Anybody got any photos?
我下載了犯罪現場的照片
Yeah. I downloaded the crime scene photos.
好  給我看科爾曼
All right, show me Coleman.
在這里
Right here.
我的防彈背心呢  我給你們看點東西
Where's my vest? I want to show you something.
好
All right.
看到這些了嗎
You see these?
這是M10沖鋒槍的子彈
That's from a mac-10.
再看這個
Now look at this.
看到撞擊形成的蘑菇狀圖案了嗎
You see how the impact mushrooms out?
那是九頭蛇半被甲彈才有的
That's from a semi-jacketed hydra-shok round.
它會發出高昂尖銳的聲音
It makes a high-pitched scream.
我確信我聽到了
And I know that I heard it.
這是執法機關配備的
That's law enforcement issue.
自己人誤傷的嗎
Friendly fire?
不  所有的警察都在向餐廳里開槍
No. All those cops were shooting into the diner.
這顆來自牧師的相同方向
The round came from the same direction as the preacher.
我不知道是誰先開的槍
Ok, I don't know who shot first,
但我知道所有被害人都和臺球房有關
but I do know that every victim's connected to the pool hall.
唯一失蹤的就是黛娜
The only one missing is Dinah.
去把她找出來
Go find her.
你想干什么  黛娜
What are you doing, Dinah?
拜托  歐文
Come on, Owen.
放過我吧
Just let me be.
我不像牧師那么頑固
I'm not stubborn like the preacher.
我不會妨礙你的
I won't give you any trouble.
你知道我不會說出去的
You know I ain't gonna say nothin'.
你最好不要
Oh, I know you better not.
求你了
Please.
歐文  我不會告訴任何人的
Owen, I won't tell anyone.
我發誓
I swear.
走吧  來
Let's go. Come on.
好好好
Ok. Ok, ok, ok.
快走
Move it.
探員
Agent.
他怎么樣了
How is he?
奇跡般的幸運
Incredibly lucky.
子彈再往右兩毫米
Two millimeters to the right
就會穿透頸動脈
and the bullet would have torn through the carotid artery.
一些小血管受了傷
It nicked some smaller vessels,
不過我們已經止住了血
but we've stopped the bleeding.
你可以去看他了
You can see him now.
他怎么樣了
Hey, how is he?
太好了
Great.
好
Ok.
謝謝  艾麗克斯
Thanks, Alex.
再見
Bye.
斯賓塞在恢復了
Spence is in recovery.
很好
Good.
這孩子太聰明了  死不了
The kid's too smart to die.
可能是利用知識的力量改變了彈道
Probably rerouted the bullets by power of suggestion.
我嚇壞了
I was scared.
我也是
Yeah, I was, too.
看起來在某人闖進來之前
Well, it looks like she packed a few things
她打包了一些行李
before someone forced their way in here.
卡車還在外面停著
Truck's still out front.
她看起來像是個母親嗎
She strike you as the mothering type?
除非你付她錢吧  怎么了
Well, if you pay her for it. Why?
她把這個裱起來了
She has this framed.
這在她箱子的底層
It was in the bottom of her bag,
所以這可能是她最先打包的東西之一
so that probably means it was one of the first things she packed.
肯定對她來說很重要
It must be very important to her.
霍奇  她消失了
Yeah, Hotch. She's gone,
但看來她不是自愿離開的
but it doesn't look like she went willingly.
的確不是
No, she didn't.
到警局匯合
Meet us at the station.
好
Right.
你們在哪里找到她的
Where did you guys find her?
她正準備離開鎮子
Trying to get out of town.
麥格雷戈警員發現她在13街上飛馳
Deputy McGregor found her flying down Route 13.
讓她靠邊停車  她還拒捕
When he pulled her over, she resisted arrest.
我想和麥格雷戈警員談談
I'd like to talk to deputy McGregor.
他回去巡邏了  你想知道什么
Well, he's back out there. What do you need to know?
她當時開的什么車
What was she driving?
他沒說  可能是她的卡車吧  怎么了
He didn't say. Her truck, I presume. Why?
只是好奇
Just curious.
反正也不重要了
Well, it doesn't matter much.
我們現在抓到她了
It looks like we got her now.
這一切肯定都是她做的
She's gotta be behind all this.
可能忍受不了一直被牧師控制
Probably got tired of the preacher controlling her
企圖自己奪權
and pulled a power play.
你們應該有形容這種行為的
I'm sure you guys have a proper word
專業術語吧
for that kind of behavior.
蛇蝎心腸
Devious.
失陪了  伙計們
Excuse me, folks.
黛娜的卡車還停在她家
Dinah's truck was still at her place.
我們得和她談談
We need to talk to her.
非常樂意
Happy to do it.
你好  黛娜
Hi, Dinah.
有時候調查人員會變得視野狹隘
Sometimes investigators suffer from a form of tunnel vision.
尤其當有自己人被害的時候
especially when one of their own gets killed.
他們停止詢問
They stop asking questions
然后開始依據自己的判斷推理案情
and start to frame the case around their theory.
你知道他們怎么想的嗎
Do you know what they think?
他們覺得全是你干的
They think that you did all of it,
不光是陷害牧師的事  還有殺害警長
not just the preacher, but the sheriff
以及那些女孩的事
and all of the girls, too.
但現在是這樣的
But here's the thing.
我不認為你希望那些女孩死
I don't think you wanted those girls to die.
那些女孩的事讓你感到害怕
And you were scared for those girls.
因為你曾是她們的一員
Because you were one of them.
對不對
Weren't you?
黛娜  你可以告訴我你在害怕什么
Dinah, you can tell me whatever it is you are afraid of.
我會保護你的
I will protect you.
你能保護我
You can protect me?
我們有聯邦管轄權
We have federal jurisdiction.
相框里的小男孩是誰
Who was the little boy in the picture frame?
他有七歲了嗎
He's like 7 years old?
你在浪費時間
You're wasting your time.
我跟你沒什么好說的
I got nothin' to say to you.
恕我直言  探員
With all due respect, agent,
她因拒捕被拘留
she's here under resisting arrest charges,
我猜她的罪名還遠不止于此
and my guess is there's a hell of a lot more that'll stick.
看見了嗎  視野狹隘[隧道視覺
See? Tunnel vision.
隧道的問題在于
The thing about tunnels--
可以在短時間內變得漆黑一片
they can get real dark real fast.
我現在要處理我的案子了
I'm gonna take care of my case now.
如果你不介意的話
So if you don't mind...
沒問題
Ok.
很明顯她在害怕
Well, she's definitely afraid,
但當班尼特進來時她又變得肆無忌憚
but got defiant when Bennett walked in.
有孩子的線索了嗎
You get anything about the kid?
只有她一臉的絕望
Nothing but a look of desperation.
如果她害怕失去什么人
If she has someone to lose,
他們肯定抓住了她的把柄
they hold all the cards.
外面說
Outside.
加西亞查了一下
So Garcia did some digging
結果發現特拉維斯·亨森
and it turns out that Travis Henson,
餐廳里的第三個死者
the third victim from the diner,
還是名線人
was also a confidential informant.
-科爾曼的嗎  -不是
- For Coleman? - No.
是名叫歐文·麥格雷戈的授勛警官的
For a decorated deputy named Owen Mcgregor.
你是說逮捕黛娜
You mean the same deputy who arrested Dinah
卻沒等登記完就走了的那名警官
but didn't stick around to book her?
這就解釋了科爾曼體內的九頭蛇子彈
It explains the hydra-shok rounds found in Coleman
還有為什么所有受害者都那么害怕
and why all the victims were afraid.
每個人都說"他們"會找上她們的
Each one reported "they" were gonna get them.
如果"他們"指得并不只是歐文·麥格雷戈呢
What if "they" is more than just this Owen Mcgregor?
如果是整個警局呢
What if it's the whole force?
我跟你說  科爾曼不可能是黑警
I'm telling you, Coleman was not a dirty cop.
沒錯  但是他才當了一年警長
No, but he's only been sheriff for a year.
所以他是局外人  這就是他被殺的原因
So he's the outsider. That's what got him killed.
這么多受害者  他們到底在保護什么
It's a massive body count. What the hell are they protecting?
一種生活方式
A way of life?
像這樣的腐敗可以讓很多人賺大錢
Corruption like this can make a lot of people a lot of money.
你也從來沒見過這個麥格雷戈嗎
And you never met this Mcgregor?
我們著陸時他剛休假
He'd just finished his 4/40 when we landed.
這倒挺方便
Convenient.
他現在該回來了
He's back on the clock now.
他會去哪兒
Where would he go?
壞消息  那名探員活下來了
Bad news. That agent's gonna make it.
要我幫忙嗎
You need my help?
不用
No.
我來處理就好
I'll take care of it.
如果他醒來
It'll be so great if he wakes up...
第一眼就看到這個肯定很高興
and this is the first thing he sees.
是啊
Yeah.
神秘博士總能讓他開心起來
The good doctor will always make him smile.
他醒來時肯定很高興
It'd be really great if he wakes up
看到我們都在盯著他
and we're all--ooh-- staring at him.
所以我站到那邊去
So, I'm gonna go stand over here.
急診
怎么了
What's wrong?
不要相信任何人  親愛的
Trust no one, my friend.
為什么
Why?
貪污腐敗
Corruption.
這么有組織的犯罪需要一個強勢的領導者
Something this organized needs a strong leader.
我們認為是歐文·麥格雷戈警官
We think it's deputy Owen Mcgregor.
還有一個可靠的副手
And there's a second-in-command who appears trustworthy
但是得有權限和方法來造成大規模的傷害
but has the access and the skill set to do a lot of damage.
班尼特警官很符合這點
Deputy Bennett is presenting as that.
他們陷害牧師和黛娜
They framed the preacher and Dinah.
她還在擔驚受怕中
She's still alive and terrified.
她和牧師經營著賣淫集團
She ran the prostitution ring with the preacher,
但是她肯定還參與了不少其它事
but she must play a bigger part in the rest of this.
很顯然她活著比死了更有價值
She's clearly worth more alive than dead.
目前為止
For now.
我們可以給她點好處
We could offer her something,
讓她相信我們
get her to trust us.
我們之前也見過這種情況
We've seen this before.
我們找到她孩子  沒準她就開口了
We find her kid and maybe she'll talk.
那看看加西亞能不能找到他
Let's see if Garcia can find him.
其他人去找出還有誰參與了這件事
The rest of us need to figure out who else is involved.
加西亞
Hey, Garcia.
我找到了果汁  肉湯  還有果凍
Hi. I found juice, broth, and jell-o.
很平淡無奇  但是他需要卡路里
Super bland, but he needs the calories.
等這摘掉后  我就跟鮑里斯·卡洛夫一樣了
When this comes off, I'm gonna look just like Boris Karloff.
英國演員  曾出演弗蘭肯斯坦
是啊  再化點綠色的妝
Yeah. A little green makeup
你就成了萬圣節最棒的著裝了
and you'll have the best halloween costume ever.
大家都沒事  放心吧
Everybody's fine. Don't worry.
不是擔心
I'm not.
又皺眉頭啦
You've got that furrowed brow.
你要不要看看誰醒了啊
Will you look who's still awake.
你能跟她說聲可以走了嗎  拜托
Can you tell her she can go now, please?
我沒事了  艾麗克斯  去幫他們吧
I'm ok, Alex. Go help the team.
好吧  我走了
All right. I'm out of here.
真高興你醒了
I'm glad you're awake.
謝謝
Thank you.
好了
Ok.
是要果汁  肉湯  還是果凍
Juice, broth, or Jell-O!
我最喜歡吃的果凍
Jell-O, my favorite.
你們在外面待了挺長時間的
You guys were out there a long time.
有什么要跟我們分享的嗎
Anything we should know about?
出去透透氣而已
Just getting some fresh air.
好吧
Ok.
黛娜的退稅單上
Dinah didn't claim any dependents
一個親屬都沒填
when she filed her tax returns.
主動報稅得過獎勵
Bonus points for checking in with Uncle Sam.
她至少在這方面還是守紀守法的
At least that part of her life's in order.
她是本地人  她母親住在16公里外
She's from around here. Mom lives 10 miles away.
太奇怪了
This is weird.
她母親帶著一個在白金漢小學上一年級的孩子
Her mom has a first-grader enrolled at Buckingham Elementary.
一個78歲的老人什么時候
What are the chances a 78-year old
會有個上一年級的孩子
has a first-grader?
-孩子叫什么  -喬什
- What's his name? - Josh.
我把資料都發給你們
I'm sending all the information out.
好的  謝了  加西亞
All right, thanks, Garcia.
吃吧
Eat that.
加西亞查到了黛娜的兒子
So Garcia tracked down Dinah's son,
住得離這兒不遠
who's living close to here, but, um,
不過好多雙眼睛盯著我呢  得你們其他人去
I've got eyes all over me, so someone else should go.
里德博士怎么樣了
How's Dr. Reid?
他醒了  會沒事的
He's awake. He's gonna be fine.
太好了
That's good to hear.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我們開車兜兜風去  我把情況告訴你
Let's take a car ride. I'll fill you in.
小潔  把資料發給我們
JJ, send us the info.
沒問題
Will do.
科爾曼來這兒才一年
We knew Coleman had only been here a year,
不過看這個
but get this.
他也是前任去世了才來接替他的
He replaced a sheriff who also died.
他的前任怎么死的
Of what?
藥物過敏
Allergic reaction to medication.
他當時正在醫院治療槍傷
He was in the hospital recovering from a gunshot wound.
誰開的槍
Who shot him?
那人逃掉了
Got away.
報告上說一開始是去突擊掃毒的
Report says it was a drug raid
后來演變成了槍戰
that ended in automatic gunfire.
報告誰寫的
Who wrote that report?
歐文·麥格雷戈
Owen McGregor.
就是說之前那個警長發現手下貪腐
So the old sheriff realized that his office was corrupt.
他手下就設計把他殺了  似曾相識啊
They staged a murder. That sounds familiar.
可能那些小姐目睹了事情經過
Then if the prostitutes witnessed it
威脅要告發他們
and threatened to tell,
所以才招致殺身之禍
that's what got them killed.
那位警長哪一天死的
On what date did the sheriff die?
上面說是一年前的三月二十日
It says here March 20, a year ago.
盧卡斯·瓦格納也是在那天死的
The same day as the first victim Lucas Wagner.
歐文花了整整一年時間策劃出這場終極游戲
So Owen's had a whole year to figure out his end game.
一切都是因那天晚上而起
It all started on that night.
你去看看能不能讓黛娜松口
You need to see if you can get Dinah talking,
然后你去查查歐文·麥格雷戈的底細
and you need to find out everything you can about Owen McGregor.
我們能保證喬什的安全
你進去干嘛
What was that about?
看看她肯不肯松口
Just seeing if she wanted to talk.
像黛娜這樣的人就是心術不正
A person like Dinah's gotta have some demons.
好像天生就不會走正道
It's like she was born into bad choices.
喂
Hello.
洛倫扎納
收到了嗎
Hey, did you get it?
我們要查的就是那名警察
That's the cop we're looking for.
那邊嗎
That way?
收到
Affirmative.
他就在那兒  對吧
He's right there, isn't he?
他正在護士站
He's at the nurses station.
我得回里德那兒去
Oh, I gotta get back to Reid.
加西亞  回房間把門關上
Garcia, get in that room and shut the door.
好了  現在怎么辦
Ok, I did that. Now what?
你集中精神按我說的做
I need you to focus and I need you to listen to me.
能做到嗎
Can you do that?
能  能  能做到  能做到
Yes. Yes. I can do that! I can do that!
房間里有輪椅嗎
Is there a wheelchair in the room?
有
Yes.
讓里德坐上去
Get Reid in it!
那可不容易啊
That is not gonna be easy.
拿上他的衣物包  他的槍在里面
Then get his patient bag. His gun is in there.
天吶  什么
Oh, my God! What?
佩內洛普  你得出來到走廊上去
Penelope, I need you to get out in that hallway.
好的
Ok.
你沒事吧
You ok?
現在放心了
Relieved.
我還以為今天會糟糕透頂呢
I thought it was gonna be the worst day.
我真怕里德挺不過來
I was so afraid Reid wasn't gonna make it.
不過他挺過來了
Yeah, but he did.
再看看我們
And look at us now.
正要去保護一個孩子
We're gonna go protect a kid
讓他媽媽有重來的機會
and give his mom another chance.
是啊  再好不過了
Yeah. Doesn't get much better.
沒有比警察貪腐更糟的事兒了
Dirty cops doesn't get much worse.
這工作挺奇怪的  是吧
It's funny about this job, isn't it?
從一個極端走到另一個極端
The extremes.
對啊  不過一向如此
Yeah. Well, it's always been that way.
我職業生涯最輝煌的日子
One of the best days of my career
結果變成了最悲催的日子
turned out to be one of the worst.
1983年7月16日
July 16, 1983.
一起兒童綁架案演變成了謀殺案
Child abduction turned murder.
我們抓住了那家伙  他殺害了5個男孩兒
The guy we nabbed killed 5 boys,
而那幾個男孩兒我們都已經查明身份了
and they were cases we had already tracked.
知道他
It was such a victory
再也不能危害其他人了  可謂是大獲全勝
in knowing that we'd stopped him from hurting anyone else.
等我到了家  我的東西都被打包了
When I got home, my bags were packed.
卡洛琳再也受不了了
Carolyn had had enough.
我忘了我們的周年紀念
I had forgotten our anniversary
又一次忘了
again.
還忘了許多對我來說
As well as all the other little things
不那么重要的事情  因為...
that didn't seem important because...
拯救生命高于一切
saving lives trumped everything.
我犧牲了我們的生活
So I let ours die.
這就是人生平衡的奇妙之處
That's the great balance of life.
總會有辦法打擊你
Always finds a way to knock your legs away.
怎么回事
What the hell?
他們在去接那個孩子的路上
They're headed to get the kid.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
他們知道了
They figured it out.
我就知道我該自己搞定
I knew I should have handled this myself.
請大家盡量前往出口
If you can, make your way to the exit.
請不要使用電梯
Not the elevator, please.
你要我們怎么做
What do you want us to do?
殺了他們
Kill them.
我還以為你說過情況不會變得更糟
Thought you said it doesn't get any worse.
無信號
沒有最糟只有更糟
Until it does.
他們真的會向聯邦探員開槍嗎
Are they really gonna shoot Federal Agents?
他們是那種寧死也不肯進監獄的警察
They're cops who'd rather die than get locked up.
他們已經走投無路了
They're desperate.
她沖著你來了
She's coming to you.
你子彈上膛了嗎
Have you got one in the chamber?
上了
Yep.
開戰吧
Let's roll.
他們撞了我們
They rammed us.
我們開了幾槍
We got off a few rounds.
他們逃走了
They got away.
我們搞砸了
We--we messed up.
17號高速發生槍戰  所有單位請回答
We got a 10-71 on Highway 17. All units respond.
安全地點不是很遠
The safe house isn't too far away.
黛娜會在那里等我們嗎
And Dinah will be waiting for us?
我們可能會先到
Well, we may get there first.
喬什  我能給你照張相給你媽媽看嗎
Hey, Josh, can I take a photo for your mom?
好的
OK.
來一個燦爛的笑容
OK. Now, you want to give me a big smile?
很好  好了  去吧
Great. OK, go ahead.
他現在和探員們在一起
He's with agents now.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你愿意合作了嗎
Do you agree to cooperate?
愿意  只要能把我從這鬼地方弄出去
Yes. Just get me the hell out of here.
我們走吧
Let's go.
我奉命不能讓她離開那個屋子
I've got orders she's not to leave the premises.
你就和你上司說是我把她帶走了
You can tell your boss she's leaving with me.
你去和你上司說她不能走
You tell yours she's not.
放開我
Let go of me.
除非你想因為妨礙聯邦探員調查
Unless you want to arrested for obstruction
而被拘捕  否則放開她
of a federal investigation, let her go.
他走了吧
He's gone, right?
他走了  他們讓我們回來了
He is gone. They're letting us back in.
太好了  你成功了  寶貝
All right, good. You did it, baby girl.
我做了點壞事
I lost a couple karma points,
不過總算成功了
but, uh-huh, I did it.
我大概五分鐘后到
All right, I will be there in about 5 minutes.
我知道你和第一個被害人
I know you and the first victims
目睹了歐文警官謀殺前警長的過程
witnessed deputy Owen kill the former sheriff.
他為什么放過了你
Why did he spare you?
因為他知道我能助他獲取財富
When he looks at me, he sees dollar signs.
他通過臺球廳運營一切  我完全保持緘默
He runs everything through the pool hall and I don't say a word,
因為如果我說出去  他會傷害我兒子
'cause if I did, he'd hurt my son.
而且他幫手眾多
And he's got a lot of help.
即使是那些沒有收取好處的人
I mean, even if people aren't getting paid off,
也因為害怕什么也不敢說
they're all too scared to say anything.
也就是說整個警局都知道
So the whole force knows?
相當一部分人知道
Enough of them.
他進行的是什么交易
What's he dealing?
什么都有
Everything.
他搞到一切能搞到的東西
He gets all the product he can
然后賣給出價更高的買家
and then sells it to the higher bidder.
他從哪里搞到的貨
Where did he get it.
偷的
Steals it.
他甚至跨國界販賣人口
He even smuggles people across the border.
他們能怎么辦
What are they gonna do?
他戴著警徽  他們沒有
He wears a badge, they don't.
麥格雷戈警官如果知道
Where would deputy McGregor go now
我們快查到他了會去哪里
that he knows we're closing in?
去城市邊緣一個他管控的垃圾場
To a junkyard he controls on the edge of town.
他最后一招會是調虎離山
He's final move's going to be a distraction.
比如呢
Like what?
你還好嗎
You ok?
還好  就是感覺很累
Yeah. I'm just really tired.
那是肯定的  你得睡一會
Of course you are. You need to get some sleep.
但是你怎么睡得著呢  你在醫院里
Oh, but how can you sleep? 'Cause you're in a hospital
總有人來給你做檢查
where people are always poking you.
他一個小時前吃了藥
He had his meds an hour ago.
這是術后抗生素
Yeah, post-op antibiotics.
他也打過這些了
Yeah, he had those, too.
這是什么
Which ones?
羧芐青霉素  這個不行
Carbenicillin? No, that's not right.
我對β-內酰胺類抗生素有強烈過敏
I have a severe reaction to beta lactams.
我不能注射這個
I can't have that.
你的病歷里沒寫
That's not in your chart.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
加西亞  他身上有槍
Garcia! He has a gun!
他還在動
He's moving.
好吧
Ok.
我不知道開槍這么大動靜
I didn't know how loud.
我聽不見了  因為我心臟跳得
I can't hear, 'cause my heart
像是要跳出來了
feels like it's gonna come out.
這可能嗎
Can that happen?
一個人的心臟有可能跳出胸口嗎
Physically, can your heart burst out of your chest?
這些聲響是什么
And what is this ringing?
每次坐完飛機  我耳朵都得嗡嗡響一個禮拜
My ears don't pop for like a week after I fly,
要是這次也那樣的話  我會瘋的
and if this is like that, that's gonna drive me bonkers.
我在嚷嗎  因為我覺得自己可能在嚷
Am I yelling? Because it feels like I might be yelling.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
你能聽見我講話嗎
Can you hear me?
可以  我聽見了  現在心里舒服多了
Yeah, I heard that. That makes it better.
謝謝你這么說
Thank you for saying that.
謝謝你這么做
Thank you for doing it.
好了  你沒事了
Ok. You're ok.
好了
Ok.
喬什
Oh, Josh.
我的小寶貝
Oh, my sweet boy.
最近的聯邦支援離這里有一個小時的路程
The closest federal support is an hour away.
我已經聯系過突擊隊了
I've called the rangers.
他們多久能到
How long for them?
三十分鐘
30 minutes.
摩根  一切都還好嗎
Hey, Morgan. Is everything ok?
一切都好  別擔心
Everything's fine. Don't worry.
這一切都是為了引開我們
It was all a big distraction.
這肯定也是麥格雷戈謝幕曲的一部分
It's gotta be part of McGregor's end game.
他去垃圾場了  我把地址發給你
He's headed to a junkyard. I'll send you the address.
聯邦調查局
FBI!
沒事了
Ok. It's ok.
一切都會沒事的
It's gonna be ok.
看啊
Huh. Look at this.
都坐滿了
It's a booked flight.
也許經過這么戰功赫赫的一年
Maybe with the year we've all had,
上級會批給我們一架大點的飛機
uh, the brass will give us a bigger plane, you know.
好吧  等你的好消息
Yeah. Let me know how that goes.
突擊隊怎么看這件事
What did the rangers think?
他們以前也見過這種事
Sadly, they've seen this before.
他們清理那個地方就得忙上一陣了
They're going to have their hands full cleaning the place up.
霍奇  別跟我說咱們又有新案子
Hotch, don't tell me we have another case.
我們要打道回府嗎
Are we turning the plane around?
不用
No.
不用  我們大家都回家睡個好覺
No, we're gonna go home and get some sleep.
希望能補個好覺
Lots of it, I hope.
我決定現在就開始
I am starting now.
你確定你沒事嗎
You sure you're ok?
我感覺很好
I feel great.
也許是夸張了點
Ah, that's overselling it.
作為脖子中了一槍的人來說
I, uh, I feel great
我這狀態算是很棒的了
considering I just got shot in the neck.
把這個放哪
Where do you want this?
就放在那吧
Any -- right there is fine.
好了  你該好好睡一覺了
Ok. So, you should get some sleep.
你還好吧
You all right?
昨天看到你那個樣子
Yesterday touched a nerve
讓我觸動不小
saw you like that.
伊森是誰
Who's Ethan?
我兒子
My son.
他去世時才九歲
He was 9 when he died.
醫生說是神經系統的問題
Doctors said it was neurological,
但他們也說不出個所以然來
but they didn't have a name for it.
至今仍是如此  這讓我很抓狂
Still don't. That drove me crazy.
我都說不清楚到底是什么
No word to put to this thing
奪走了我的至愛
that took away my greatest love.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
雖然生著病  他也一直在成長
He kept growing despite his disease.
我最后一次躺在他身邊時
The last time I lay beside him,
他都差不多跟我一邊高了
he was almost as long as me.
他已經做好準備了
He was ready to go.
但我還沒做好道別的準備
But I wasn't ready to say good-bye.
我求他睜開眼睛
I begged him to open his eyes.
最殘忍的是  我能想象到
And the cruelest part was that I could see
他二十歲時的樣子
who he would be at 20,
但我知道他卻永遠看不到那一天了
but I knew he'd never get there.
伊森這個名字很好聽
Ethan is a great name.
是啊
Yeah.
是"不朽"的意思
It means enduring.
很適合
It's fitting.
你和詹姆斯從來沒放棄過彼此
You and James never let go of one another.
你有沒有過那種感覺
Have you ever had that feeling
好像你的未來在你的身后
that your future is somehow behind you?
經常
All the time.
我也是
I did, too.
但實際不是這樣的
But it isn't.
伊森要是長大了  肯定跟你很像
Ethan would have been a lot like you.
謝謝你在我醒來時守在我的身邊
Thank you for being there when I woke up.
這對我意義重大
That meant a lot.
應該的
Of course.
再見  艾麗克斯
Bye, Alex.
*放手讓我走*
*Let me go*
*我們都無法逃脫重力*
*Gravity gets us all*
*只是想告訴你*
*Just thought you should know*
*在明早的晨光里*
*In tomorrow's morning light*
*一切看起來就會不那么可怕*
*Things will look a lot less frightening*
*而現在  而現在*
*And now, and now*
*而現在*
*And now*
*也許只是*
*Maybe just*
*也許我們*
*Maybe we*
聯邦調查局特別探員
*可能在*
*Could be*
*譜寫歷史*
*Write history*
*也許我*
*Maybe I...*
"我們必須心甘情愿
"We must be willing
放棄我們所計劃的生活
to get rid of the life we planned
才能迎來正在等待我們的生活"
so as to have the life that is waiting for us."
約瑟夫·坎貝爾[美國神話作者]
Joseph Campbell.
*不要忘記我們曾說過的話*
*Let's not forget what we said*
*在你能放手讓我走之前*
*Let's hold it instead*
*就牢牢記住這些話吧*
*Till you let me go*